# Daniele Moltisanti

R&D Data Scientist - Machine Learning Engineer

Linkedin: Portfolio: Email: Contact: www.linkedin.com/in/daniele-moltisanti https://daniele21.github.io danielemoltisanti@live.it +39 3337337311

## Profile

I'm a Data Scientist passionate about making advantage of data for solving real case problems, through AI algorithms. Specialized in NLP techniques and Technical Manager of Conversational AI projects. I'm Google Cloud Certified, experienced also in Computer Vision algorithms and investing my free time into Time-Series Forecasting algorithms for finance.

## **Technical Skills**

- Languages: Python, Matlab, SQL, Java, C, Bash- Tools: Git, Docker, Jupyter Notebook

- Frameworks: Pytorch, Tensorflow 2.x, Keras, Rasa 2.x, Flask

- Libraries: Scikit-Learn, NLTK, Spacy, Pandas, Numpy, Scipy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, OpenCV

- Soft Skills: Problem solving, Perseverance, Leadership, Cooperation

# Work Experience

R&D Data Scientist

01/2021 - present

Youtility Center S.p.A Milan, Italy

- Managing Techical aspects of Conversational AI projects (chatbots)
- Achieved over 90% accuracy relative to NLU (natural language understanding) models
- Achieved over 90% accuracy relative to NLG (natural language generation) models
- Handled complex chatbot (more then 150 intents)
- Taked care of the pipeline automation for CI/CD of chatbots
- Making use of AWS services, such as storage (S3) and laaS (EC2)

**Tools**: Python, Tensorflow 2.x, AWS, Git, Rasa 2.x, Docker, NLTK, Spacy, SQL

• Data Scientist 05/2020 - 01/2021

Accenture S.p.A Milan, Italy

- Developed a custom NER model for the document understanding task related to Financial Industry, starting from a small dataset
- Achieved over 95% accuracy relative to the entity classification of documents, even if the small input data
- R&D relative to NLP tasks such as Entity Extraction and Named Entity Recognition (NER)
- Developed a custom Computer Vision denoising model for noise reduction in documents, achieving relevant improvements for the OCR task
- Developed projects making use of Google Cloud Platform (GCP) services, such as IaaS (compute instances), PaaS (app engine), storage

Tools: Python, Pytorch, Tensorflow 2.x, Keras, CUDA, Git, OpenCV, Google Cloud Platform

#### Master Thesis Researcher

09/2019 - 04/2020

Politecnico di Milano Milano Milano

Title: "Anomaly Detection through Ganomaly: patch-wise training and transfer learning"

Goals: introducing improvements to the Ganomaly state-of-the-art for Anomaly Detection, in order to achieve an more efficent training for any-dimension images and a more effective performances through the trasfer learning technique

Tools: Python, Pytorch, CUDA, Git

Al Engineer - Internship

09/2018 - 02/2019

Reply S.p.A Milan, Italy

- Contributed in the development of a virtual assistant, where I developed the cognitive model for classifying fashion items in images.
- Experienced with IBM Watson services
- Integrated the cognitive model into the telegram channel, handling RestAPI

Tools: Python, Pytorch, CUDA, Git, IBM Watson

#### Education

•	Master's Degree in Computer Science and Engineering Politecnico di Milano	09/2019 - 04/2020 Milan, Italy
•	Athens Programme - course: From Complexity to Intelligence Telecom Paris-Tech	03/2019 - 03/2019 Paris, French
•	Erasmus project Universitat Politecnica de Valencia	01/2018 - 06/2018 Valencia, Spain
•	Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering Politecnico di Milano	09/2014 - 07/2017 Milan, Italy
Certifications		
•	Associate Cloud Engineer - Google Cloud Certification	10/2020
•	Spanish B2 level - FIDESCU	10/2017
•	English Toeic - ETS Global B.V.	09/2017
Courses		
•	Coursera	
	MLOps Fundamentals	03/2021
	Machine Learning for Trading Specialization	03/2021
	Sequence Models Specialization	05/2020
•	Qwiklabs	
	Sequence Models for Time Series and NLP on Google Cloud	12/2020
	Advanced ML: ML Infrastracture	09/2020
	Image Understanding with Tensorflow on GCP	11/2020

# **Personal Projects**

• **Algorithmic Trading** | Python, Pytorch, Git, Pandas

03/2021 - present

- Developing a time-series forecasting model for stock trends, basing on meta-labeling techique.
- Analysis, Feature engieneering and pair trading startegy are used for the trading algorithm
- **DL Soccer Prediction** | Python, Pytorch, Flask, Git, Pandas

09/2020 - present

- Developed a soccer match prediction model for european tournaments, based on a custom deep learning network, achiving over 130% of gain in 3/4 tournament rounds.
- Developed an MLOps pipeline, triggered by API calls, for training automations and model updates

You can see all my personal projects on my portfolio